ROHITH VIJAY

Software Engineer, Front-End

Mobile: +1 (548) 577 8889 | E-mail: rohithvijaypersonal@gmail.com

Current Location: Waterloo|

Skype ID: live: cid.6fe79738405830cb | LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/rohith-vijay

OBJECTIVE

A Front-End Developer with 6 years of experience having a strong background in developing robust, secure, and user-friendly web applications in various verticals such as e-Commerce, Health care and Banking and Financial services using JavaScript frameworks like React and Angular.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

MAR 2022 - AUG 2023

Quest Global, Trivandrum, India | Clients: Canon Medical, General Electric, Philips KEY PROJECTS AND ROLES

• Role as Senior Software Engineer | Client - Canon Medical

Developing and maintaining web applications using Angular framework to support various healthcare-related processes and systems.

- Designing and Implementation of responsive layouts, forms, and interactive components using Angular, HTML, CSS and Bootstrap.
- Worked closely with healthcare professionals and stakeholders to understand their requirements and translate them into functional features. This involves implementing complex business logic and workflows within the Angular application.
- Implementation and Integration of REST APIs into the application using RXJS library in Angular.
- Implementation of Angular features like life cycle hooks, interaction between components, custom directives/pipes across different components in the project.
- Implementation of SSE event in server side with the help of C# to identify live events on the website.
- Followed responsive design principles across different devices like PC, laptop, mobile phones etc. using media queries.
- Followed UX design principles to improve user experience.
- Conducted thorough testing (unit, integration and system tests) and debugging to identify and resolve issues, ensuring optimal functionality and user satisfaction.
- Clear and comprehensive documentation of design decisions and diagrams to understand the overall structure and design principles.
- Ensured overall product quality throughout the entire software development life cycle.
- Mentored Junior developers and trainees about clean code principles, code organization, and writing scalable Angular applications.
- Committed and maintained code in GIT repository.

SENIOR UI DEVELOPER

SEP 2019 - MAR 2022

Reflections Info Systems, Trivandrum, India KEY PROJECTS AND ROLES -

PASS ML - Role as Senior UI Developer. (From 2021-2022)

Collaborated with internal teams and vendors to fix and improve products and services. Implementation of responsive layouts, forms, and interactive components using Angular, HTML, CSS and Bootstrap. Implementation and Integration of REST APIs into the application using RXJS library in Angular. Identification and fixing bugs, as well

as optimizing performance.

• SVAST - Role as UI Developer. (From 2019-2021)

Designing and developing robust solutions to meet client requirements for functionality, scalability and performance. Worked with back-end programmers to implement REST API using Angular. Wrote understandable HTML, SCSS and typescript code using JavaScript frameworks like Angular to build responsive web-based applications. Followed Agile development methodology to ensure product quality. Regular meetings and communication with team members to keep the track of the tasks in the projects.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

JUL 2017 - SEP 2019

Cycloides Technologies, Trivandrum, India | Clients: Tune Protect, Policaro Group, Commissionaires, Onedles KEY PROJECT AND ROLES -

• TUNE PROTECT - Role as a React Developer. (2019)

Translated design teams UX wireframes and mockups into responsive, interactive features using React (JSX) and building responsive websites for the website. Integration of API's and unit testing.

• My Recycle Buddy - Role as an Angular Developer. (2018-2019)

Translated design teams UX wireframes and mockups into responsive, interactive features using HTML, CSS and JavaScript. Integration of REST API's using Angular.

• Commissionaires - Role as an Ionic Developer. (2018-2019)

Developed UI design and API integrations for mobile applications using technology like ionic framework which used ionic libraries and JavaScript framework like angular 2.

Onedles - Role as an Angular JS Developer. (2017-2018)

Web development using HTML, CSS, Angular 1 and PHP for building and developing UI components. Involved in building responsive web designs and fixing browser compatibility issues. Identification, fixing and tracking the bugs in the Redmine tool.

KEY RESPONSIBILITIES

- ✓ Proficient in writing clean and well-structured **HTML**, **CSS**, and **JavaScript** code, adhering to industry best practices and coding standards.
- √ Hands-on-Experience in JavaScript frameworks like Angular and React.
- ✓ Hands-on-Experience in TypeScript and ES6.
- ✓ Hands-on-Experience in **Bootstrap**, **Material UI**, **Tailwind** and CSS preprocessors like **SASS** and **SCSS**.
- ✓ Dedicated to writing **clean and well-documented** code, utilizing inline comments and JSDoc annotations to enhance code maintainability and facilitate collaboration within development teams.
- ✓ Strong Knowledge in React Router, React Hooks, React Lifecycle and Reconciliation algorithm.
- ✓ Followed Responsive Design Principles to create websites using Mobile-first approach, Media queries, Flex concept, and Fluid Grids.
- ✓ Familiarity with writing **responsive** and accessible web content, ensuring **compatibility** across different devices and assistive technologies.
- ✓ Strong Knowledge of tools like **Webpack** and **Babel**.
- ✓ Strong attention to detail in writing and reviewing code, ensuring accuracy, efficiency, and maintainability.
- ✓ Proactive in staying updated with the latest industry trends and best practices in front-end development, and effectively communicating these insights to the team.
- ✓ Logging of bugs and tracking of bugs in **JIRA**, **Redmine** etc.
- √ Good Knowledge in Agile Methodologies, SDLC and BDD.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Project/Quality Management JIRA, Redmine
- Version Control System/DevOps SVN, GIT, GitHub
- Database Management SQL Server, Oracle 12c, MySQL queries

- Operating Systems Linux, Windows
- Tools Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code
- Frameworks JavaScript, Angular, React
- Methodologies Agile (Scrum), SDLC, Waterfall

CERTIFICATION

Pursuing AWS Solution Architect Associate Certification

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY – COMPUTER SCIENCE MG University, India

2016